# Jeremy Moseley

jeremy.moseley@gmail.com 1-415-926-1955

Jeremy is a focused engineer who is intrigued by the design and architecture of distributed systems. He has experience with distributed systems in Scala, Python, and Typescript/Javascript, and has dabbled in everything from HTML to databases and operating systems.

**GitHub** jmoseley **LinkedIn** Jeremy Moseley

#### **SKILLS**

DEVELOPMENT TOOLS	Visual Studio Code, Intellij, PyCharm, Sublime Text 2/3, Git, SBT
DISTRIBUTED SYSTEMS	Queues, Shared Memory, Databases, Redis, AWS, SQS, SNS, RabbitMQ, Memcache, Sharding, Distributed System Design, APIs, API Design
LANGUAGES/FRAMEWORK	( <b>S</b> Play, Slick, Scala, Java, Bash, Javascript, Typescript, ES6, Node, Python, XQuery/XPath, XML, Meteor JS, Bootstrap, PHP, React, Redux
DATABASE	MySQL, PostgreSQL, RDS, ORM, Slick, SQLAlchemy
CLOUD	AWS, ECS, EC2, S3, Route53, SNS, SQS, Heroku, Hasura

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Convoy

**Software Engineer** Nov 2016 - Present

Small agile team working to disrupt the freight industry using product driven development. Engineering work focusses on mobile and web apps built around a micro-service architecture using cutting edge technology like React and Node.

- Mentoring more junior engineers at various stages of their careers (non-traditional background & first job, lightly experienced & starting to tackle larger scope, and traditional background & somewhat experienced).
- Working on projects with Org wide scope, evangelizing and pushing on solutions to large technical project with organizational scope and a large breadth of stakeholders.
- Led the team to developed the first version of a system wide stress testing plan, used to ensure that our systems can handle extreme near-term growth.
- Learned Javascript and Node quickly become a productive member of the team, working closely with Product to develop useful features for both internal and external users.
- Maintain and extend systems that allow complex integrations with external customer systems.
- Technology: Typescript/Javascript, PostgreSQL, AWS, React

# **Inkling Systems Inc.**

#### Import/Export Software Engineer 3 May 2015 - Nov 2016

The Import/Export squad manages all methods for bring content into and out of the Inkling platform, providing infrastructure for converting content from Word to HTML, HTML to EPUB and PDF, as well as conversion to internal formats for Inkling's internal readers.

- Reduced content export errors by 10%, increasing customer satisfaction and reducing customer support overhead.
- Architected a new microservice using the Play framework and an SQS task processor to provide a scalable worker system to allow easy scaling for demand
- Developed a successful Seattle intern program
- Technology: Scala, Java, Play, AWS, SQS, PostgreSQL, Python, XML

# **Inkling Systems Inc.**

**Infrastructure Engineer** Jun 2014 - May 2015

The infrastructure team manages infrastructure tooling and AWS deployment of the Inkling stack. Supports other engineering teams to make deployment and infrastructure management more reliable and easier to work with.

- Implemented a state-of-the-art distributed log systems that handles 30 million events a day.
- Migrated Inkling's deployment and packaging system to Docker
- Significantly reduced downtime caused by deployments
- Increasing engineering efficiency when developing and deploying new services
- Operated as a member of the emergency on-call rotation
- Technology: Scala, AWS, Python, Bash, PostgreSQL, Docker

# **Inkling Systems Inc.**

**Platform Engineering Intern** Sep 2013 - Dec 2013

Developed and deployed an XML database, and developed supporting features in the core Python API

- Wrote complex XQuery scripts and API interfaces
- Technology: BaseX, XPath, XQuery, XML, Python

## **Internet Shakespeare Editions**

Part-time Developer Sep 2012 - Aug 2013

Part-time member of a team while in studying, using XQuery and XPath to maintain and develop new features for a long-term academic project. Designed a mobile experience, as well as used XQuery and XPath to process and transform marked up content in a variety of interesting ways, depending on how the content was being consumed.

- Designed a mobile-first experience from scratch
- Wrote complex and performant XQuery scripts to transform marked up content on the fly for mobile consumption
- Technology: eXistDB, XPath, XQuery, XML, CSS, Javascript

## **Vineyard Networks**

**Co-op Engineer** Jan 2012 - Aug 2012

Developed deep packet inspection (DPI) plugins for a software package that runs on network hardware.

- Analyzed raw network traffic to extract patterns for various traffic types (HTTP, TCP, UDP, etc)
- Designed code to analyze Facebook, Google, Steam, and a variety of other application streams
- Technology: C++

### **EDUCATION**

## **University of Victoria**

Aug 2009 - May 2014 Bachelor - Software Engineering GPA: 6.39

# **SAIT Polytechnic**

Jan 2006 - Dec 2007 Associates Degree - Computer Engineering Technology GPA: 3.9

#### LANGUAGES

English

#### **INTERESTS**

mountain biking

#### technology

- technology
- research
- user experience
- future